BENJAMIN FOLKS

E: <u>bfolks2@gmail.com</u> • M: (630)-217-5872 1143 W Wrightwood Ave #1F, Chicago, IL 60614 https://github.com/bfolks2, www.benfolks.com

AEROSPACE-SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Multi-faceted engineer with experience working on project teams in numerous fast-paced environments. I aim to combine my Aerospace Engineering Degree and real-world aviation experience as an *FAA*Certified Instrument-Rated Pilot with my software development experience in a profession environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python	JavaScript/jQuery	 VB.NET
• Django	• Ember.js	HTML/CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

RedShelf • Chicago, IL • January 2018 – Present

Web software company providing digital content for educational institutions (www.redshelf.com)

Full-Stack Software Engineer

- Work on a small development team to address product-driven enhancement/bug tickets while simultaneously building out entirely new business-driven applications
- Created new application utilizing Django-Rest-Framework and Ember.js
 - Built REST API's for standard CRUD methods, as well as other custom operations, utilized by the front-end Ember application
 - Service-based encapsulation for all Python objects, where API Logic Mangers are used for all cross-service related queries
- Constructed unit, integration, and acceptance (Selenium) tests, completing an initiative to increase coverage across the code-base to over 90%
- Collaborated with development teams in an Agile Environment, using SCRUM methodology

AdThrill • Chicago, IL • December 2017 – Present, (Part-Time)

Start-up website for users to watch and rate advertisements (adthrill-prod.herokuapp.com)

Lead Python Engineer

- Rebuilt model structure within the Python/Django application in order to successfully utilize the Django ORM in creating a user-business search algorithm
- Completed overhaul of front/back-end site components to allow for AJAX requests between JS Video Player and Django database.
- Deployed the first build of the site for use in live production

DP Technology – ESPRIT • Rosemont, IL • July 2012 – December 2017

Developer and supplier of computer-aided manufacturing (CAM) software.

Senior Applications Engineer

- Manage customer-specific enhancement proposals from concept to finished product
- Utilize customer feedback obtained during trainings and consultations to plan and create additional VB.NET/VBA applications within the software API for improving software UX
- Travel onsite to aerospace and US government clients to oversee technical projects, including NASA Glenn, Woodward Inc, Northstar Aerospace, Tinker AFB

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering
UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS • Urbana-Champaign, IL • 2011
FAA Certified Private Pilot - Instrument Rating